Guide to the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations oral history collection 2011.019
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Minna Aslama Horowitz, 2013 December 13; 2011.019.072; 14768
  In the interview, Horowitz discusses her experiences living in the Crown Heights and Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhoods of Brooklyn; relationship with her husband, a Russian American Jew from Brooklyn, New York; and impressions of the differences between Finnish and American culture in regards to academia, economic security, and community identity. Interview conducted by Liza Zapol.
  United States |x Emigration and immigration; Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Education, Higher -- New York (State) -- New York; Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.); Finland; Finns |z New York (State) |z New York; Interethnic marriage; Cultural diversity; Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)
- Aya Hosch, 2013 December 10; 2011.019.071; 14956
  Aya Hosch was born to a Colombian mother and Syrian father in Rockville, Maryland and raised in Dallas, Texas. Hosch received a B.A. in political science and linguistics from the University of Texas at Arlington and served as a public policy and international affairs law fellow at the University of California at Berkeley.
  In the interview, Hosch discusses her racial, ethnic, and religious identities; educational experiences; romantic relationships; work on political campaigns; parents' courtship, marriage, and divorce; and mother's conversion to Islam. Interview conducted by Rebecca Jacobs.
  Washington (D.C.); Sex role; Dallas (Tex.); Racially mixed families; Racially ambiguous people; United States |x Emigration and immigration; Racially mixed people; Education |z Texas; Conversion |x Islam; Muslims |z Texas |z Dallas
- Andrew Hoyles and Nayantara Sen, 2014 February 14; 2011.019.074; 14937
  Andrew Hoyles was born to African American parents in Watertown, New York and raised in Detroit and Okenos, Michigan. Hoyles received a B.S. in biosystems engineering from Michigan State University in Lansing, Michigan. He worked as a compost instructor and manager at the Lower East Side Ecology Center in Manhattan, New York.
  Nayantara Sen was born to Indian parents in Calcutta, India. She attended boarding school in Dehradun, India and immigrated to the United States at the age of fifteen. Sen received a B.A. in English literature from Michigan State University in Lansing and attended graduate school at New York University in New York City. She worked as a project associate for Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations at the Brooklyn Historical Society.
  In the interviews, Hoyles and Sen discuss their childhoods; courtship; experiences as an interfaith and interracial couple; encounters with racism; and impressions of gentrification in New York City. Hoyles discusses his family life and experiences with racism and racial stereotyping in Michigan. Sen discusses her impressions of British influences at her boarding school in India; relationships with family members; and move to Michigan as a teenager. Interviews conducted by Manissa Maharawal.
  East Indian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Gentrification |z New York (State) |z New York; African Americans |z Michigan; Boarding schools |z India |z Dehra Dun; Interfaith families; Interracial dating; Hinduism; Interfaith dating; Lansing (Mich.); Racial stereotyping |z Michigan; Queer identity; United States |x Emigration and immigration; Racially mixed families; India
- Teresa Ish, 2011 November 12; 2011.019.002; 14794
  Teresa Ish was born to a Chinese-Malaysian mother and Swedish father in Fresno, California and raised near Clovis, California. Ish received a B.A. in environmental studies and biology and an M.S. in marine science from the University of California at Santa Cruz. Ish co-founded Fish Wise, a nonprofit organization dedicated to seafood sustainability.
  In the interview, Ish discusses her Chinese and Swedish heritage; family's culinary and holiday traditions; parents' courtship in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia; childhood in California; and perspectives on raising a family in Brooklyn, New York. Interview conducted by April Reynosa.
  Race identity; Racially mixed people; Marine sciences; Swedish Americans |z California; Racially mixed families; Cooking |x Social aspects; Santa Cruz (Calif.); Kuala Lumpur (Malaysia); Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Chinese Americans |z California
- Melissa Jimenez, 2012 May 11; 2011.019.029; 14947
  Melissa Jimenez was born to a Filipino American mother and a Dominican American father and raised in New York City. Jiminez lived in New York City with her Italian American husband and their daughter.
  In the interview, Jimenez discusses her racial identity; connections to her Dominican and Filipino heritage; childhood with her maternal grandmother, her primary caregiver; parents' courtship, marriage, and divorce; courtship and marriage to her Italian American husband; and experiences raising their daughter in New York City. Interview conducted by Nadia Williams.
  Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Race identity; Racially ambiguous people; Filipinos |z New York (State) |z New York; Parenthood; Dominican Americans |z New York (State) |z New York
- Ari Joseph, 2012 June 6; 2011.019.033; 14946
  Ari Joseph was born to a mixed race Peruvian Catholic mother and a white American Jewish father and raised in New York City. Joseph received a B.A. from Middlebury College in Vermont and an M.P.S. from New York University in New York City. He worked for Hostelling International in New York City.
  In the interview, Joseph discusses his racial identity; encounters with racism; educational experiences; parents' religious traditions; mother's Spanish and Chinese heritage; family visits to Peru; and impressions of gentrification in Brooklyn, New York. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.
  Oral history with Ari Joseph's partner, Emily Pinkowitz, 2011.019.039.
  Catholicism; Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Peru; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Racially mixed people; Racially mixed families; Race identity; Judaism; Interfaith families; Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- Madeleine Kanai, 2011 December 10; 2011.019.005; 14944
  Madeleine Kanai was born to a white American mother and a mixed race Japanese father in Kobe, Japan and raised in Kobe and Lexington, Kentucky. Kanai received a B.A. in international studies from DePaul University in Chicago, Illinois and an M.A. in globalization from the University of Sussex in Falmer, England. She worked in communications and marketing in the retail industry, as well as for the Loving Day Project, an organization dedicated to fighting racial prejudice through education.
  In the interview, Kanai discusses her racial identity; racially ambiguous appearance; involvement with mixed race community groups; courtship and marriage to her husband, who is also mixed race; father's ancestry and heritage; mother's experiences as a white woman in Japan; early childhood in Japan; and family's move to Kentucky. Interview conducted by Katrina Grigg-Saito.
  Racially mixed people; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed children; Race identity; Loving Day; Japanese Americans |z Kentucky |z Lexington; Lexington (Ky.); Interracial marriage; Kobe-shi (Japan); United States |x Emigration and immigration
- June Kaplan, 2013 June 24; 2011.019.053; 14929
  June Kaplan was born to German Jewish parents and raised in Brooklyn, New York. Kaplan received an undergraduate degree from Queens College and an M.S.W. from New York University, both located in New York City. She was employed as a social worker and lived in Westchester, New York.
  In the interview, Kaplan discusses her childhood in the Bushwick neighborhood of Brooklyn and the Kew Gardens neighborhood of Queens; parents' flight from Nazi Germany; career in social work; and experiences working with United States Air Force service members and their families. Interview conducted by Charis Shafer.
  Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Jews, Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Jews, German |z New York (State) |z New York; Social workers |z New York (State) |z New York; Education -- New York (State) -- Kings County; United States |x Emigration and immigration; Bushwick (New York, N.Y.); Kew Gardens (New York, N.Y.)
- Svetlana Kitto, 2014 June 5; 2011.019.099; 14790
  Svetlana Kitto was born to a Latvian American mother and an English father in London, England and raised in Los Angeles, California. Kitto received a B.A. in English and creative writing from Mills College in Oakland, California and an M.A. in oral history from Columbia University in New York City. She worked as a copyeditor and oral historian.
  In the interview, Kitto discusses her childhood in Los Angeles, California; commitment to activism; sexual orientation; interest in creative writing; maternal grandparents' experiences as Holocaust survivors; father's childhood experiences at an alternative school; and parents' courtship, marriage, and divorce. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.
  Drug addiction |z California |z Los Angeles; Education |z California; United States |x Emigration and immigration; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Queer identity; England; Latvia; Los Angeles (Calif.)
- Julie Kline, 2012 January 13; 2011.019.012; 14960
  Julie Kline was born to a white American Lutheran mother and a white American Jewish father and raised in Oakland, California. Kline received a B.F.A. in acting from DePaul University in Chicago, Illinois. She lived in Brooklyn, New York and worked as an actor, director, and theatre instructor.
  In the interview, Kline discusses her family; maternal grandparents' courtship during World War II; paternal grandparents' divorce; move to Brooklyn; involvement in New York City's theatre community; romantic relationships; Jewish and Pagan religious convictions; and childhood health issues. Interview conducted by Liza Zapol.
  Interfaith families; Judaism; Neopaganism; Religious identity; Actors |z New York (State) |z Kings County; United States -- Armed Forces -- World War, 1939-1945; Theater |z New York (State) |z New York; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Oakland (Calif.)
- Corbin Laedlein, 2013 March 8; 2011.019.043; 14811
  Corbin Laedlein was born to an African American mother and a white American father in Brooklyn, New York. He was raised in the Red Hook and Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhoods of Brooklyn. Laedlein majored in Africana studies at Rutgers University in Piscataway, New Jersey, where he co-founded, Fusion: The Rutgers Union of Mixed People. Laedlein worked for Added Value, an urban agriculture nonprofit organization in Brooklyn, New York.
  In the interview, Laedlein discuss his childhood in Brooklyn, New York; parents' courtship and marriage; impressions of gentrification, class, and privilege in the Bedford-Stuyvesant and Red Hook neighborhoods of Brooklyn; and experiences as a student in the New York City public school system. Interview conducted by Amna Ahmad.
  Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Racism in education |z New York (State) |z New York; African Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Passing (Identity); Privilege; Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.); Red Hook (New York, N.Y.)
- Daniel Latorre, 2013 September 20; 2011.019.065; 14961
  Daniel Latorre was born to a Norwegian American mother and a Colombian father in Bogotá, Colombia. He was raised in Bogotá, San Diego, California, and Minneapolis, Minnesota. Latorre attended the University of Wisconsin at Madison and founded Wise City, a civic engagement and product strategy company in New York City.
  In the interview, Latorre discusses his racial identity; encounters with racism in San Diego and Minneapolis; educational experiences; career path; romantic relationships; parents' courtship and marriage; siblings' connection to their Colombian heritage; and experience during the September 11 terrorist attacks. Interview conducted by Rebecca Jacobs.
  Minneapolis (Minn.); San Diego (Calif.); Colombians |z Minnesota |z Minneapolis; Racially mixed people; September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001; Bogotá (Colombia); Greenpoint (New York, N.Y.); Colombians |z California |z San Diego; Passing (Identity); Race identity; Racially mixed families
- Thomas Lax, 2012 June 16; 2011.019.036; 14963
  Thomas Lax was born to a mixed race French mother and a white American Jewish father and raised on the Upper West Side, Manhattan. Lax received a B.A. in Africana studies and art from Brown University in Providence, Rhode Island and an M.A. in modern art from Columbia University in New York City. He worked as a curator at the Studio Museum in Harlem and the Museum of Modern Art in New York City.
  Access to the interview is restricted. The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.
  Race identity; Queer identity; Interfaith families; Homophobia; Upper West Side (New York, N.Y.); United States |x Emigration and immigration; Racially mixed people; Racially mixed families; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); African Americans |z New York (State) |z New York
- Catherine Leung, 2012 November 27; 2011.019.040; 14942
  Catherine Leung was born to a mixed heritage American mother and a Chinese American father and raised in the Park Slope and DUMBO neighborhoods of Brooklyn. She attended Packer Collegiate Institute in Brooklyn, New York and Smith College in Northampton, Massachusetts.
  In the interview, Leung discusses her racial identity; encounters with racism and racial stereotypes; parents' courtship, marriage, and divorce; father's connection to Chinese culture; mother's Assyrian heritage; and involvement in community building organizations at Smith College. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.
  Racial stereotyping; Race identity; Education, Higher |z Massachusetts |z Northampton; Education -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Assyrians |z New York (State) |z New York; Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); DUMBO (New York, N.Y.); Student life and customs |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Racially mixed people; Racially mixed families
- Hansraj Maharawal, 2012 June 18; 2011.019.034; 14949
  Hansraj Maharawal was born to a Scottish American mother and an Indian father and raised in the Prospect Heights and Park Slope neighborhoods of Brooklyn. Maharawal received a B.A. in visual arts from Sarah Lawrence College in Bronxville, New York. He lived in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn and worked as an artist and assistant designer.
  In the interview, Maharawal discusses his racial identity; encounters with racism; educational experiences; childhood in the Park Slope and Prospect Heights neighborhoods of Brooklyn; parents' courtship, marriage, and divorce; father's emigration from India; and involvement in the artistic community. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.
  Oral history with Hansraj Maharawal's sister, Manissa Maharawal, 2011.019.093.; Oral history with Hansraj Maharawal's cousin, Neela Miller, 2011.019.079; Oral history with Hansraj Maharawal's cousin, Rajiv Miller, 2011.019.092; Oral history with Hansraj Maharawal's friend, Vilray Bolles, 2011.019.017.023.
  East Indian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.); Racially mixed people; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Race identity; Racially mixed families; Education |z New York (State); Interracial marriage
- Manissa Maharawal, 2014 May 22; 2011.019.093; 14788
  Manissa Maharawal was born to a white American mother and an Indian father in New York City. She was raised in the Prospect Heights and Park Slope neighborhoods of Brooklyn. Maharawal received a B.A. from Sarah Lawrence College in Bronxville, New York. She pursued a Ph.D. in anthropology at the Graduate Center at City University of New York.
  In the interview, Maharawal discusses her racial identity; childhood in the Prospect Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn; academic and social experiences in public and private schools; impressions of gentrification in Brooklyn, New York; and experiences with racism and prejudice following the 1991 Crown Heights Riots and the September 11, 2001 Terrorist Attacks. Interview conducted by Svetlana Kitto.
  Oral history with Manissa Maharawal's brother, Hansraj Maharawal, 2011.019.034.; oral history with Manissa Maharawal's cousin, Neela Miller, 2011.019.079.; oral history with Manissa Maharawal's cousin, Rajiv Miller, 2011.019.092.; oral history with Manissa Maharawal's partner Zoltan Gluck, 2011.019.094.
  India; Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.); September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001; United States |x Emigration and immigration; Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Race identity; East Indian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Bullying in schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- Michelle Materre, 2014 June 6; 2011.019.097; 14789
  Michelle Materre was born to African American parents and raised in Chicago, Illinois. Materre received a M.Ed. in educational media from Boston College in Massachusetts. She worked in film marketing and distribution, and was employed as a professor at The New School in New York City.
  In the interview, Materre discusses her Haitian, Native American, French, and German Jewish ancestry; family's roots in New Orleans, Louisiana; experiences with racially-motivated violence in Georgia and Louisiana; involvement in the Civil Rights Movement; social and academic experiences at a predominantly white private high school; work in the film industry; and impressions of contemporary political issues. Interview conducted by Jennifer Scott.
  Slavery |z United States; African Americans |z Illinois |z Chicago; Civil rights movements |z United States |y 20th century; Chicago (Ill.); Independent films; New Orleans (La.); Race identity; Racially mixed families; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Shameeka Mattis, 2013 July 11; 2011.019.054; 14804
  Shameeka Mattis was born to an African American mother and a Vincentian father and raised in Brooklyn, New York. Mattis received a B.A. in English and sociology from the State University of New York at Binghamton and an M.S.W. from the University of Pennsylvania in Philadelphia. She worked as an assistant director at the Vera Institute of Justice, a nonprofit center for justice policy and practice in New York City.
  In the interview, Mattis discusses her childhood in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn; crime and gentrification in Brooklyn, New York; and courtship and marriage to her Haitian American wife. Interview conducted by Charis Shafer.
  Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.); Haitian Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.); Same-sex marriage; Queer identity; Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.); Red Hook (New York, N.Y.); Caribbean Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Crime -- New York (State) -- Kings County
- Leslie Martinez, 2014 June 6; 2011.019.096; 14792
  Leslie Martinez was born to Honduran parents in New York City and raised in the Bronx, New York. Martinez received a B.A. in history from Baruch College and an M.S.Ed.in leadership and museum education from Bank Street College of Education, both in New York City. Martinez worked at several museums in New York City and as a program manager at Cool Culture, an organization that provides low-income families with free access to New York City's cultural institutions.
  In the interview, Leslie Martinez discusses her family's Garifuna heritage; parents' immigration to the Bronx, New York from Limon, Honduras; and experiences as a black Spanish speaker in New York City. Interview conducted by Jennifer Scott.
  African Americans |z New York (State) |z Bronx County; Race identity; Spanish language; Cultural identity; Bronx (New York, N.Y.); United States |x Emigration and immigration; Garifuna (Caribbean people) |z New York (State) |z New York; West Indian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Honduras
- Taneka Maxwell, 2013 April 21; 2011.019.058; 14820
  Taneka Maxwell was born to African American parents on a U.S. Army base in Heidelberg, Germany. She was raised in Brooklyn, New York and Anniston, Alabama. Maxwell received a B.A.Sc in communication and media studies from Hofstra University in Hempstead, New York. She wrote a children's book under the pseudonym "Pink Maxwell" and worked as an account analyst at Morgan Stanley.
  In the interview, Maxwell discusses her childhood in the Brownsville neighborhood of Brooklyn; friendships in the Brownsville community; family's roots in Anniston and Birmingham, Alabama; relatives' migration from Alabama to New York City in the 1930s; and losing her mother and other family members to cancer. Interview conducted by Dorothy Saint Jean.
  African Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Education |z New York (State); Bereavement in adolescence; African Americans |z Alabama |z Anniston; Migration, Internal |z United States; Anniston (Ala.); Brownsville (New York, N.Y.)
- Pattie McGill and Ralph McGill, 2013 August 3; 2011.019.059; 14805
  Pattie McGill was born to African American parents and raised in the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn. She worked as a school aide in a public school in East New York.
  Ralph McGill was born to an Italian mother and a white American father and raised in the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn. He worked as a mechanic in his family's auto business.
  In the interview, the McGills discuss their childhoods in the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn; perceptions of cultural changes in East New York; courtship, marriage, and raising children in New York City; and plans for retirement. Interview conducted by Dorothy Saint Jean.
  Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Racially mixed families; Parenthood; East New York (New York, N.Y.)
- Aglaye Metellus, 2014 June 16; 2011.019.089; 14807
  Aglaye Metellus was born to a Haitian mother and a Cuban father and raised in Nyack, New York. Metellus studied psychology and health services administration at Lehman College and received an M.S. in drug regulatory affairs from Long Island University, both located in New York City. She worked in the pharmaceutical industry.
  In the interview, Metellus discusses her Haitian and Cuban heritage; parents' courtship; experiences growing up with ten siblings; and impressions of multiculturalism and diversity in Nyack, New York. Interview conducted by Jennifer Scott.
  Nyack (N.Y.); Racially mixed families; Cultural diversity; Haitians |z New York (State) |z Nyack; Racially mixed people; Cubans |z New York (State) |z Nyack
- Neela Miller, 2014 January 16; 2011.019.079; 14818
  Neela Miller was born to an Indian mother and a white American father in Brooklyn, New York and raised in Norwood, New Jersey. Miller received a B.F.A. in sculpture from Pratt Institute in Brooklyn, New York and worked for several yoga and art organizations.
  In the interview, Miller discusses her Indian heritage; racial identity; Hindu convictions; parents' courtship and marriage; relationship with her husband; and negotiations surrounding food, culture and faith in her marriage. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.